<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Plant Care &#8211; Herb Gardening 101</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/plant-care/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 08:00:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Basil Pruning Hacks for Instagram-Worthy Plants and Flavorful Feasts #PlantGoals</title>
		<link>/basil-pruning-hacks-for-instagram-worthy-plants-and-flavorful-feasts-plantgoals/</link>
					<comments>/basil-pruning-hacks-for-instagram-worthy-plants-and-flavorful-feasts-plantgoals/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jessica]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plant Care]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So, you&#8217;re like me and totally can&#8217;t resist the smell and taste of basil, huh? I mean, it&#8217;s irresistible, right? So, you&#8217;ve decided to grow some, maybe in your backyard or in those cute pots by your kitchen window. But now you&#8217;re wondering, &#8220;How do I make you look like the thick, lush plants I ... <a title="Basil Pruning Hacks for Instagram-Worthy Plants and Flavorful Feasts #PlantGoals" class="read-more" href="/basil-pruning-hacks-for-instagram-worthy-plants-and-flavorful-feasts-plantgoals/" aria-label="More on Basil Pruning Hacks for Instagram-Worthy Plants and Flavorful Feasts #PlantGoals">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So, you&#8217;re like me and totally can&#8217;t resist the smell and taste of basil, huh? I mean, it&#8217;s irresistible, right? So, you&#8217;ve decided to grow some, maybe in your backyard or in those cute pots by your kitchen window. But now you&#8217;re wondering, &#8220;How do I make you look like the thick, lush plants I see on Insta?&#8221; Don&#8217;t stress, girl(or boy), I&#8217;ve got you covered!</p>
<h2>Ready to join the basil pruning club? Let&#8217;s roll!</h2>
<p>So, what&#8217;s the deal with pruning basil anyway?</p>
<p>Well, it&#8217;s all about helping it grow and getting loads of yummy basil. And guess what? Doesn&#8217;t matter if your basil is hanging out in pots, garden beds, or if it&#8217;s Italian, lemon, or Thai basil. Pruning is like the perfect filter—it works for all. But what&#8217;s the real tea on pruning?</p>
<h3>Harvesting</h3>
<p>OMG, there&#8217;s nothing like fresh basil on your homemade pizza or in a killer salad. The more you prune, the more basil you get. It&#8217;s a total win-win!</p>
<h3>Boosting growth</h3>
<p>This sounds super weird, I know. Like, how can cutting off part of a plant make it grow more? But seriously, when you snip the stems back to a new set of leaves, it forces those leaves to grow, giving you double the basil. It&#8217;s pretty much magic!</p>
<h3>Stopping flowers</h3>
<p>If your basil starts to bloom, it&#8217;s gonna focus more on that than growing the good stuff for us. So, we gotta keep those flowers under control!</p>
<p>When&#8217;s the best time to start pruning?</p>
<p>You know what they say, timing is everything. For basil, start early when the plant is about as tall as your smartphone and has three to four sets of leaves. Picture this: each plant is a single stem, and when you nip that stem, poof, you get double-stemmed plants. That&#8217;s like double the likes on your basil pics!</p>
<h2>Pruning 101: The Rules of the Game</h2>
<p>When you&#8217;re ready to harvest, don&#8217;t just yank off leaves. That&#8217;s like so not cool. Instead, you&#8217;re gonna want to trim the top parts of the stems. And if your basil is store-bought and already taller than your water bottle? Chill, you can still trim them down to make them grow even more.</p>
<p>After that initial trim (like a dramatic new haircut), give your basil a couple of weeks to regrow before the next trim. I usually do a mini trim every fortnight during summer to keep that growth on point.</p>
<h2>Let&#8217;s get down to it: How to Prune</h2>
<p>Here comes the fun part! You can totally use your fingers, or garden shears, or herb scissors. Just be careful not to tear the stems. That&#8217;s not cool for our little basil buddies.</p>
<p>Before you start, have a proper look at your plant, like when you&#8217;re picking out a fab outfit. Spot a pair of leaves with two little buds just peeking out. You&#8217;re gonna snip the main stem just above these little guys. It&#8217;s totally up to you how much you wanna cut. A bit to add some spice to your dinner, or a lot if you&#8217;re in the mood for pesto or saving some basil for later.</p>
<h3>Flower alert: Keep them in check!</h3>
<p>Remember how I said basil plants can start flowering? If that happens, time to get those snips out and chop off those flower buds. It&#8217;s kinda like playing whack-a-mole, only you&#8217;re hunting for flower buds. Yeah, you&#8217;ll have to check every week or so, but it&#8217;s worth it for that sweet, sweet basil.</p>
<h2>Preserve Your Basil</h2>
<p>Okay, so you&#8217;ve trimmed your basil and it&#8217;s looking good. Now what? You could dry the leaves, or even freeze them. I&#8217;m all for freezing. It&#8217;s super easy. Just chop &#8217;em up, add a bit of olive oil, and throw them in the freezer. Then when it&#8217;s all cold and wintry, you&#8217;ve got a piece of summer waiting for your dinner.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s it, babes! Now you&#8217;re a boss at pruning basil. It&#8217;s as easy as nailing a TikTok dance and twice as fun. So, what are you waiting for? Get out there and start snipping! You&#8217;ll be surprised how much your basil plants will slay. And remember, the more you prune, the more basil you&#8217;ll have for all your foodie adventures!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/basil-pruning-hacks-for-instagram-worthy-plants-and-flavorful-feasts-plantgoals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
